<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lettrss.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://lettrss.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-11T00:39:41-08:00</updated><id>https://lettrss.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">lettrss.com</title><subtitle>lettrss syndicates public domain books via RSS.</subtitle><author><name>Pablo Enoc</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Wonderful Wizard of Oz - Introduction</title><link href="https://lettrss.com/2025/11/11/introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Wonderful Wizard of Oz - Introduction" /><published>2025-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://lettrss.com/2025/11/11/introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lettrss.com/2025/11/11/introduction.html"><![CDATA[<p>Folklore, legends, myths and fairy tales have followed childhood through the ages, for every healthy youngster has a wholesome and instinctive love for stories fantastic, marvelous and manifestly unreal. The winged fairies of Grimm and Andersen have brought more happiness to childish hearts than all other human creations.</p>

<p>Yet the old time fairy tale, having served for generations, may now be classed as “historical” in the children’s library; for the time has come for a series of newer “wonder tales” in which the stereotyped genie, dwarf and fairy are eliminated, together with all the horrible and bloodcurdling incidents devised by their authors to point a fearsome moral to each tale. Modern education includes morality; therefore the modern child seeks only entertainment in its wonder tales and gladly dispenses with all disagreeable incident.</p>

<p>Having this thought in mind, the story of <em>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</em> was written solely to please children of today. It aspires to being a modernized fairy tale, in which the wonderment and joy are retained and the heartaches and nightmares are left out.</p>

<p>L. Frank Baum <br />
Chicago, April, 1900.</p>]]></content><author><name>L. Frank Baum</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Folklore, legends, myths and fairy tales have followed childhood through the ages, for every healthy youngster has a wholesome and instinctive love for stories fantastic, marvelous and manifestly unreal. The winged fairies of Grimm and Andersen have brought more happiness to childish hearts than all other human creations.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to lettrss</title><link href="https://lettrss.com/2025/11/10/welcome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to lettrss" /><published>2025-11-10T19:52:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-11-10T19:52:00-08:00</updated><id>https://lettrss.com/2025/11/10/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lettrss.com/2025/11/10/welcome.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi,</p>

<p>Thank you for checking out lettrss!</p>

<p>If you are reading these words it means you have successfully subscribed to the feed in your reader of choice.</p>

<p>Since the second part of the Wicked movie is coming out on November 21 in the United States, I thought it’d be fun to start this RSS project with <em>The Wonderful Wizard of Oz</em> by L. Frank Baum.</p>

<p>I hope you enjoy reading along with this first book.</p>

<p>Please feel free to contact me with any feedback or comments.</p>

<p>Warm regards,<br />
Pablo Enoc</p>

<p><a href="mailto:pablo@enocc.com?subject=RE%3A%20Welcome%20to%20lettrss">Reply via e-mail</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Pablo Enoc</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi,]]></summary></entry></feed>